Mohammad Shakil Mahmud

Problem Solver

Road: 4, Block B, Section 6, Mirpur, Dhaka 1216 (+880) 1314058365 shakilmahmud.cse2020@gmail.com



Objective

Strong problem-solving with excellent interpersonal skills and Bachelor's degree. Seeking a head-hunting company to utilize a solid understanding of configuration management, and practical knowledge of code debugging as a Software Engineer. Coming with attitude and hunger for learning and 5 years of competitive Programming experience.

EXPERIENCE

Walton Hi-Tech Industries PLC.

Deputy Asst Director (Software Engineer)

March 2022 - PRESENT.

EDUCATION

Daffodil International University- Bsc in CSE

Jan 2016 - jan 2020

Sristy College Of Tangail- HSC

2014

BNB High School, Mirzapur-SSC

2012

Skills & Abilities

Programming

• C,C++,Python, Php ,Javascript, Html,CSS .

Advance Programming And Frameworks

• Django, ReactJS, Bootstrap 4, Tailwind css, Jinja Template, Ajax, jQuery, Axios, Rest API.

Database

MySQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL.

Other Experience And Management

· GIT, Trello, Heroku.

Projects

Django CRUD with Vue

Technologies: Vue Js, Django.

Link: https://github.com/ShakilMahmud/django_crud

Django API Service

Technologies: Django.

Link: https://github.com/ShakilMahmud/Api_Service_Project

Django Chat

Technologies : Django, Channel.

Link:

https://github.com/ShakilMahmud/Django-Project/tree/master/channel/chat

Live Costing Dashboard : A dashboard implemented to all Production Lines of Walton to Monitor Live Costing (Real time) and MP Efficiency.

Technologies: React Js, Laravel.

My Roles: DB Design, API Development.

Link: Confidential.

Item Benchmarking and comparing

Technologies: Php.

Link: Confidential.

Drag and sorting

Technologies: Php,Jquery,MySQL.

Link: Confidential.

MyNote

Technologies: Django, React Js, MySQL.

Link: https://github.com/ShakilMahmud/Note-App

MyGoal

Technologies:

Backend : Django Rest API,Django-REST-Knox. Frontend : React js,Tailwind css,Antd,React MUI.

Link : Confidential.

Status : Running.

WORK EXPERIENCE

ACM Head

DIU Computer and Programming Club

12/2018 - 12/2019 Daffodil International University

Achievements/Tasks

- Arranged programming and problem solving training class for beginner programmer
- Arranged programming contest for beginner programmer titled DIU Take Off Programming Contest

Contest Administrator and Judging Director

DIU Computer and Programming Club

01/2017 - 12/2019 Daffodil International University

Achievements/Tasks

- Contest Administrator and Judging Director of DIU Take Off Programming Contest
- Problem setter of DIU Take Off Programming Contest

Problem Solving Skills

I have solved almost 1300 problems in different online judges Platforms

- Uva Online Judge (270) terminator_c
- Codeforces (300) shakil_takeoff
- Lightoj (56) shakilmahmud84
- Stopstalk : https://www.stopstalk.com/user/profile/terminator_c
- Others (600+)

ACHIEVEMENTS

- DIU ICT Carnival programming contest (09/2018) Champion
- ACM ICPC Dhaka Regional 2018 (12/2018) Selected and participated

Student Prefect

Daffodil International University (01/2017 - 01/2019)

Student Prefect of Programming and Problem solving

course Achievements/Tasks

- Assisted weaker students to overcome their weakness in programming and problem solving
- Helped professors to their research work

Strength

Good communication skill, Quick learner, Punctual, Friendly, Dedicating.

Challenge Taken

Software System preparing and introducing 3 individual systems in Walton Tab Production line only in 7 days with developing 3 systems. Managing Full team and Users (Tab Production, R&D and QC People).

Operations : Preparing and Introducing WQMS, Production Tracking System, Repair

Maintenance System and Developing SIM tracking System, IMEI Sticker Printing System, Master

Barcode Printing System.

Result: Production for 4 Lakh Tab for BBS in Systematic way so that all tracking can be done

and all QC policies can be implemented.